Sincro: wyxchari
Ready to fire.
准备就绪
Not yet.
再等一下
She has betrayed us. She must be destroyed.
她背叛了我们, 必须被摧毁
Let her talk first.
让她先说完
They will know our numbers.
他们就能知道我们的数量了
They will also know she is alive. She is a bait.
他们也将会知道她还活着, 她是个诱饵
Victoria, tell us more about the warriors.
Victoria, 多告诉我们一些那些寒冰勇士的信息
Er, they're from Mars...
呃, 他们是从火星来的．．．
They're not important. Have you seen the propulsion unit of the spacecraft, girl?
这不重要．你有没有见到他们飞船的推进装置, 姑娘？
Oh, propulsion unit?
哦, 推进装置？
The engines!
引擎！
Oh yes. They're busy repairing them now.
是的, 他们现在正忙着维修那个
What kind are they? It's vitally important.
是什么样的？ 这可非常重要
I... I've no idea!
我．．我不知道！
Well, reactor turbine? lon jet? Anti-gravity? Think girl!
是涡轮机？fixme, 反重力的？想想！
Can you describe them to us, Victoria dear?
你能跟我们描述一下吗, 亲爱的Victoria？
Yes, yes I think so.
是的, 我觉得可以
Well hurry girl!
快点, 姑娘！
Look it isn't easy. Now I have to have time to think...
这不是太容易, 我得有点时间想想．．．
Victoria? Victoria what's happened? Are you alright? Answer me!
Victoria? Victoria．什么情况？你没事把？回答我
I'm alright.
我没事
It's the glacier. It's moving all the time.
是冰山, 它一直在移动
You're not hurt?
你没受伤吧？
The engines, tell us about the engines!
引擎, 告诉我们引擎的情况！
She has told them enough. Bring her in.
她已经透露得够多的了, 带她进来
Destroy her.
摧毁她
You are wrong Zondal. She must answer some questions first.
你错了 Zondal．她必须先回答一些问题．
Why are they so interested in our engines? Why are they afraid?
他们为什么对我们的引擎这么有兴趣？他们为什么会害怕？
There's... there's someone coming!
有．．．有什么人过来了!
Victoria... Victoria. Can you see the base from where you are?
Victoria．．Victoria．从你那里能看到基地吗？
Yes. Yes I can.
是的, 我能
Do you think you can get back to it?
你觉得你能自己回来吗？
I can give it a try.
我可以试一下
Well, get in contact again as soon as you can! Good luck!
好, 有条件的话就再次联系我们, 祝你好运！
Yes.
好
This is an automatic chemical dispenser is it not?
这是一个化学品自动合成器, 是不
Yes.
是的
How does it work?
它怎么工作？
Well, you choose the category of the article that you want by, er, indicating it on one of these little chaps here.
这样，你选择你想要的物品种类，在这些小东西上面指定
Jolly good. And er, now you dial the precise chemical formula that you want there.
很好，　然后你就按化学方程式转动这个拨号盘
May I? There's something I need rather desperately.
我试试？有一样东西是我现在迫切需要的
Oh, what's that?
哦，是什么？
Water.
水
Indeed.
真是
Ah, that's better. Now then, let's see. Jamie has vanished.
啊，这好多了．那么现在，我们看看，Jamie失踪了
Victoria's on her way back to the base.
Victoria 正在返回基地的路上
And neither of them can help us with our main problem.
他们谁也没法帮我们应对当前的主要问题
An exact description of the spacecrafts propulsion unit.
关于飞船推进装置的准确描述
That will?
这能吗?
I will.
我能
With the help of ammonium sulphide?
在硫化氨的帮助下？
We know these creatures come from Mars, don't we? What do we know about their planet's atmospheric conditions?
我们知道这些家伙是从火星来的, 是吧．我们了解他们星球的大气情况不？
Chiefly nitrogen with virtually no oxygen or hydrogen.
主要是氮气, 而氧气和氢气几乎没有
Then they're not going to enjoy this little concoction much, are they?
那他们应该不会喜欢这小瓶化合物, 是吧？
What? You mean you plan to use it as a kind of... toxic gas?
什么？你是说你打算把它用作一种．．．毒气？
Well, if I'm going to an alien spaceship it may come in handy.
呵, 如果我要上外星人的飞船, 带这个很方便
Now don't be ridiculous. We've lost Arden already.
别犯傻了, 我们已经失去了Arden
Arden fell into a trap. I know what to expect.
Arden 掉到了陷阱里, 我可知道前面有什么
I, I, I refuse to allow you to go!
我, 我, 我不批准你去
Splendid! You go instead then!
很好, 那么你去
No one can be spared! Least of all Leader Clent!
没有人是多余的, Clent 小组的人都不能(?)
I can be spared. I've done all I can here. The ioniser will work without me. I'll start getting ready then.
我是多余的, 我在这里能做的都做了．没有我离子器也能工作了, 我现在就开始准备．
But if anything goes wrong with the countdown!
但倒计时的时候万一发生点什么怎么办？
Oh, you'll manage.
哦, 你会搞定的
No!
不！
It's as simple as this: someone has to get to the spacecraft, find out what sort of propulsion unit it has,
这事很简单：必须得有人到飞船那里去, 弄明白到底用的是哪种推进装置
and bring the information back to you! Or we can't use the ioniser!
并且把信息带回给你．否则我们不敢使用离子器！
Now, who better than me?
现在, 谁比我更合适？
I've come to regard you as Penley's replacement. And, um...
我已经把你奉为 Penlay 的继任了．而且．．．
alright, alright! But it's strictly under protest!
好吧好吧, 但我还是要表示强烈异议！
Thank you.
谢谢你
How will you get the information back to us?
你怎么把信息带回给我们？
Ah. Now I don't suppose you have a, a, a, a small radio transmitter?
啊, 好像你们并没有一个．．一个微型的无线电传输器吧？
No, our video links are the only communicators available. Pure sound is no longer in use.
没有．我们唯一可用的通讯方式是视频通话．早就没在用纯语音了
Oh, well you won't see me, but you'll hear me.
哦, 那到时候你可能看不到, 但可以听到我说话
As soon as I get to the glacier face I'll switch it on and you'll overhear. I hope.
我一达到冰山表面就打开它, 你们可以偷听了．期望如此
Is that all you're taking?
你就带这些东西去吗？
Why, what else do I need?
难道, 还需要别的什么？
But the Warriors are armed!
但那些寒冰勇士是有武器的！
But I'm not going to fight a duel.
我又不是去跟他们决斗
But you must be in a position to defend yourself!
但很可能你需要自卫啊
They'll try to kill you out of hand!
他们空手也能杀死你
Oh, I don't think so.
哦, 我可不这么想
This is my defence.
这就是我的防御
But how can you rely on that? They've already proved themselves to be utterly ruthless.
你怎么能指望那个东西？事实已经证明他们是非常冷血的
I think they'll listen to me.
我想他们会听我的
You mean you're going to let them take you prisoner?
你的意思是, 你打算过去做他们的囚徒？
That is exactly what I'm going to do.
那正是我要做的
I think he's gonna wake.
我觉得他马上要醒了
Pulse isn't too good.
脉搏不是太好
His fever's gone.
已经退烧了
Well, his body is young. It will heal.
好在他身体很年轻, 会好的
Then, why you looking so worried?
那你为什么看起来还这么焦虑＞
I don't know yet. The weapons they used on him - they're curious.
我也不知道, 可能是他们对他使用的那个武器 - 他们很好奇(fixme)
Aye, scientifically designed, of course.
哈, 科学设计, 当然
This is no time for debates.
没时间争论了
Aye, it's easily said. I'll away and fetch a fresh drink.
是, 说起来倒是容易．我去拿杯水来
You'll not keep me prisoner!
我可不是你们的囚徒！
Stay still!
躺好！
No get away out of it!
别想逃出这里！
Storr!
Stop fighting!
别乱动！
You'll not keep me!
你们别想困住我！
We're your friends!
我们是朋友！
We saved your life!
我们救了你的命！
Oh, ooh.
哦, 哦
Oh my head. Ah.
哦天呐, 嗷
What you doing to me?
你把我怎么样了？
I'm going to try and ease your pain with this tranquiliser pad.
我去拿点镇定剂来, 缓解一下的的疼痛
I don't believe you!
我不相信你
Now you must trust us. We know about your friend. We may be able to help.
但你必须信任我们．我们也知道你朋友的事, 应该能帮上忙
Victoria? Well where is she?
Vicrtoria? 她在哪里？
In the alien spaceship.
在外星人飞船里
Alien?
外星人？
These warriors are not of our time. Nor of this planet.
那些寒冰勇士不是我们这个时代的, 也不是这个星球上的
So, how would you know all that?
你怎么知道这些的？
Ah, because he's a scientist. He can produce an explanation for anything.
啊, 因为他是一个科学家啊, 他能对一切事情做出解释
And you?
那你呢？
I'm a loyalist.
我是一个反对派
A loyalist!
反对派？
Ah! They've told you have they?
啊, 他们已经告诉你了, 对吧？
Aye! But there's no time to talk. I came here to rescue Victoria.
是, 但现在没有时间聊天了, 我来这里是为了救 Victoria 的
You're in no way...
你这情况不可能．．．
Oh, just you try me. Here give me a hand.
哦, 你试试． 扶我一下
He's not as bad as you say Penley.
他没有你说那么糟, Penley
Your scientists aren't always right!
你们科学家并不总是对的!
Ah ha! You hear that Penley!
哈哈, 你听到了吗 Penley?
But, your legs are still weak.
不过, 你的腿还承不了力
My legs! I can't feel my - I can't stand!
我的腿！ 我感觉不到我的 - 我站不起来了！
Oh, is this what your stupid drugs can do?
哦, 不是你们那些乱七八糟的药造成的吧？
Don't be a fool, Storr. Of course it's not the drugs.
别傻了, Storr, 当然不是药造成的
Well what is it then?
那是什么？
Well their weapons must have affected your central nervous system.
他们的武器一定是伤到了你的中枢神经系统
You mean I'm paralysed?
你是说我瘫痪了
Where is the girl?
那个女孩哪去了？
Turoc has not yet returned.
Turoc 还没有回来
He must find her.
必须得找到她
Why?
为什么？
We need her to draw an intelligent being from the base.
我们需要她才能从基地钓一个人过来
To find out the kind of reactor they use.
这样才能搞明白他们用的哪种反应器
Yes. Without the _ fuel elements we are helpless.
是的．没有那些？燃料我们就陷入无助了
And if they have them?
但如果他们有呢？
We shall take them.
我们就抢过来
Is the fuel completely run down?
燃料已经用尽了吗？
If the scientists succeed in melting the ice?
如果科学家成功地把冰都溶掉了
There will be floods.
这里就会被水淹没
No hope for our engines, then?
这样我们的引擎就没希望了
Or for us.
我们也没希望了
The gun is our only chance.
那些武器是我们唯一的机会
Help! Oh, somebody help me! Ugh! Help! Somebody!
救命！谁来帮帮我！啊, 救命, 有人吗？
Arrgghh! Oh no! No! Oh please! Help me somebody! Please help me!
啊！不, 不要, 求你了！谁来帮帮我, 救命
Well, there's nothing more I can do for him. That's the last of the tranquiliser pads.
唉, 没什么其它手段我可以帮到他了．这已经是最后一剂镇静剂了．
Do ye... understand his illness?
你清楚他的问题吗？
No, and I've no way of knowing the cause.
不, 我完全不知道是什么诱因
Well, there's one way we can save him.
要救他看来只有一条路了
How?
怎么？
To befriend the aliens.
跟外星人交朋友
Oh don't be a fool Storr!
啊, 别犯傻 Storr
Oh they'll help us. I'll talk to them. They'll understand.
他们会帮我们的, 我去找他们说．他们会理解的
But they're warriors, trained to kill.
但他们是战士, 受训的是如何杀人
Ach, only in self-defense, surely.
只是在自我防御情况下, 应该
Oh rubbish no! We've got to get the boy back to the base.
胡说八道．我们必须得把这小伙子送回基地去
No!
不！
For the boy's sake.
为了这孩子着想
Oh, ye, ye, ye trying to trap me! There's no return for me to the civilisation that Clent represents. This is where I stay.
哦, 是了, 你是想设计陷害我．我是不可能回到 Clent 所代表的那个文明世界的, 我就呆在这里
Do you think the aliens are any better? They killed Arden.
你觉得那些外星人更好？他们已经杀了 Arden
Ar, they were afraid.
他们也是害怕啊
They're ruthless, they place no value on human life.
他们是冷血的, 不会觉得人类生命有什么价值
Well I'll talk to them. Someone has to.
我还是要去跟他们谈谈, 得有人去
We don't know what they're capable of, or why they're here.
我们不知道他们能做出什么来, 也不知道他们为什么来这里
Well, I'll ask questions first, then act.
好, 我会先问问情况, 然后再看
It may be too late then.
那样也来不及
We'll see.
看看吧
No - wait! Storr, look, you don't know what you're running into!
不, 停！Storr, 你不知道你会碰到什么！
Now don't try and stop me! You look after the boy.
现在别再阻止我了, 你看好这小伙子
Storr! Storr! Storr! Storr!
Can you hear me! Help! Oh! I'm trapped!
你能听到我吗？救命！我被卡住了！
Oh, oh it's you again, is it?
哦, 怎么又是你
Has anyone passed this way?
有谁从这里过去吗？
No. Are you looking for someone?
没, 你在找谁吗？
A rather ragged fellow. Like me.
一个穿得很破的家伙, 跟我差不多
No, nobody. Not even like me.
没人, 跟我差不多的都没有
Then I'm too late. There's nothing I can do.
看来我来晚了, 这里我做不了什么了
Can I help you?
需要帮忙吗？
Well you've helped me once already. Why didn't you give me away, or stop me at the base?
你已经帮助过我一次了．你为什么不把我交过去, 或者在基地就阻止我？
Well why should I? I don't believe everything Clent tells me.
为什么我要那样？并不是 Clent 说的每一个字我都信
This boy. He's your friend.
那个小伙子, 他是你朋友吧
You know where he is? Is he hurt?
你知道他在那里？他受伤了吗？
Come this way.
到这边来
Help me please!
救命啊
Who are you?
你是谁？
Never mind about that now.
现在别管这个了吧
Would you release me please?
你能把我弄出来吗？
Wh, what happened?
怎么回事？
I run away and the warrior caught me. The ice fell...
我逃跑了, 寒冰勇士来追我, 然后冰块垮了下来．．．
You ran away? But why?
你逃跑？为什么？
The warriors - they're evil. They killed Arden. I think they want to destroy the base.
那些寒冰勇士 - 他们很邪恶, 他们杀死了 Arden, 而且他们好像还想毁灭基地
They are against the scientists?
他们是跟科学家作对的？
I know, but they won't listen. They think the ioniser is a weapon against them.
他们不肯听我的, 他们觉得离子器是用来对付他们的武器
Ah, it's true. A weapon of destruction.
也没错．一种破坏性武器
Only to destroy the ice.
它只是用来破冰的
Ah, it will destroy civilisation.
啊, 它还会破坏文明
Anyway, thank you.
不管怎么说, 谢谢你
Uh.
嗯
Ah, where were you going?
你本打算去哪儿？
Uh well, your friend, the boy.
哦, 你的朋友, 那个小伙子
Jamie! Jamie, he's alive! Oh, is he alright?
Jamie! Jamie 他还活着, 哦, 他没事吧？
Ah, he's desperately ill. I'm going for help.
啊, 他病得很严重, 我正打算去寻求帮忙
But where?
哪儿
We'd better move out of here - quickly!
我们最好离开这里 - 赶快！
Is it ready?
准备好了吗？
We are checking the motivator. Realign harmonic frequencies to target points.
我们正在检查操纵杆, 将谐振频率与目标调整到一致
When do we attack the base?
我们什么时候攻击基地？
Soon, Zondal, soon. Has Turoc returned?
快了, Zondal, 快了．Turoc 还没回来吗？
Not yet Sir.
还没有
The ice, it is alive.
这些冰, 感觉是活的
The spaceship!
飞船！
Aye.
是
You came here on purpose?
你特意到这里来的？
Of course!
当然
I'm not coming with you!
我可不跟你去了
Oh, but you must! We must! You'll - we'll be safe! They'll listen to me.
哦, 你必须！我们必须．你会 - 我们会安全的．他们会听我的
But they won't! You can't trust them.
但他们不会！你不能相信他们
Arh, they're against the scientists and the ioniser. That's good enough for me!
啊, 他们是跟科学家和离子器作对的, 对我来说这就够了
Is that your reason? I think that's wicked!
这就是你的理由？我想这也太刻毒了吧？
Ar, they'll understand.
啊, 他们会明白的
Let go of me!
放开我！
Oh!
噢
Where's Turoc?
Turoc在哪里？
He... he was crushed by the ice.
他．．他被冰块砸倒了
Oh!
嗷
I give you your life. You run away. Because of that, one of my men is dead!
我饶了你的命, 你却逃跑了．而且因为你, 我还损失了一员同胞
Honestly, it wasn't my fault!
真的, 不是我造成的！
Take her inside.
把她带进去
You're not going to kill me are you?
你没打算杀我吧, 是不？
My name is Storr. I'm a scavenger. A loyalist.
我叫 Storr, 我是一个流浪行, 一个反对派
You are from the base?
你是从基地来的吗？
No, I'm against the scientists.
不, 我跟那些科学家作对
You know nothing of their machines?
你对于他们的机器一点不懂？
No, I don't want to. Their intentions are evil. I want to help you destroy the scientists.
不懂, 也不想懂．他们的目的是邪恶的, 我想帮你们捣毁那些科学家
You. What good are you to us?
你, 你对我们有什么好处？
Oh well, I know the land around here. I've lived here all my life.
哦, 这样, 我对这里的地形很了解, 我一辈子都生活在这里
You are not a scientist. Only a local native.
你不是一个科学家, 只是一个本地土著
Useless and unnecessary.
没什么用途
Oh, but I want to help you!
但我想要帮助你们！
Now, to question the girl.
现在, 找这个女孩儿逼供
There we are!
我们到了
Good to see you again, Doctor.
很高兴再次见到了, 博士
Ah, won't be long before you're on your feet again, Jamie.
好, 用不了多久你就可以再次站起来了, Jamie
How long?
多久？
Well, that depends. You've had some sort of shock to your brain, it's affected your nervous system.
这要看情况．你的大脑受了惊吓, 影响了你的神经系统
I will walk again, though?
但我以后还是可以走路的吧？
Oh, yeah, of course you will. It's just a matter of time, that's all.
哦, 是的, 当然你会的．只是时间问题, 仅此而已
Aye, well I'll take your word on that.
啊, 我就信你的话了哈
What can we do for him?
我们可以为他做点什么？
Well the base is the only place he can be treated.
但基地是他获得治疗的唯一地方
Yes I know that, but he can't get there alone.
是的我知道这个, 但他一个人没法单独过去
That's the glacier. It's moving forward even faster.
是那些冰山, 它们移动得越来越快了
Yes. It'll flatten this place in no time at all.
是的, 很快这里就会被抹平了
Alright. I'll help you take him back.
没事, 我会帮助你把他抬回去
Well that's just it, you see. I, I can't go, there's something I must do.
目前的情况是, 你看, 我还不能回去, 还有一点事情我必须得干
Well you don't expect me to face Clent alone? That mouth-piece of the computer?
你没指望我单独去面对 Clent 吧？那个电脑传声筒？
He's got a printed circuit where his heart should be!
他的心脏部位只有一个打印电路
He's a man with a mission. I don't think he can afford to reject you.
他是一个有使命感的人．我觉得他没法拒绝你, 他承受不了这个
Well that's not the point. Anyway, what are you gonna do?
算了不说这个了． 你打算做什么？
I must speak with the warriors.
我必须跟寒冰勇士们谈谈
No Doctor!
不要, 博士
Well what can you do alone?
你自己一个人能干什么呢？
I have to see whether Victoria got away safely, and I must find out whether this
spacecraft is a danger to the ionisation program. I, I admit it won't be easy.
我必须要去看看 Victoria 有没有安全地逃脱, 我也必须弄明白这个飞船对离子项目是否存在危险．我承认这个并不简单
Doctor, if you go to the warriors you'll be their prisoner!
博士, 如果你去找他们你会变成他们的囚徒的
Their guest I hope, Jamie.
成为他们的客人, 我期望是．
Look Miss Garrett, look. The glacier's moving. That's the fifth surge today.
Garrett 小姐你看, 冰山还在你懂, 这是今天的第五次高峰．
The ioniser just isn't holding it anymore.
离子器快要撑不住了
But we daren't increase power beyond the minimal.
但我们不敢让功率超过最小值
Well I know the risk if the spaceship explodes. _ radioactivity
level. We'd only replace one disaster with an even greater one.
我知道飞船爆炸的话风险有多大, ？辐射量．我们只是将灾难换成了一个更大的灾难
But you must make a decision soon.
但你必须尽快做出一个抉择
No decision to be made yet! Computer can act only when given adequate information.
暂时还不需要抉择．必须要给出足够的信息, 电脑才能做出判断．
We still don't know enough about the alien reactor.
我们对于外星人反应器的情况还了解得不够
Suppose we never know? Suppose the Doctor never returns?
假设我们不可能搞清楚呢？假设博士不可能返回呢？
We'll face that if and when we have to.
当且仅当那个时候我们再来面对这个问题
But you must have a plan in mind, surely?
但你肯定心里已经有计划了, 对吧？
I'm pinning all my hopes on the Doctor. He must succeed.
我把所有的期望都寄托在博士身上了, 他必须成功
Here we go, Clent old chap. Wish me luck.
我们走吧, Clent 老家伙, 祝我好运
Anyone at home?
有谁在吗？
Open up. Come on, open up, I say! Very well, I shall count to ten. One... two... three... ah!
开门, 快啊, 开们． 好, 我数到十．一．．．二．．．三．．．四．．．
Who are you?
你是谁？
I never answer questions until I'm addressed properly.
如果不先问侯我的话, 我不回答任何问题
You will answer now.
你现在就要回答
Very well. You are standing in the airlock of this spacecraft.
很好, 你正站在飞船的减压舱．
Unless you answer my questions, within ten seconds I will take atmospheric pressure around you down to zero.
如果你不回答我的问题, 在10秒钟之内我就将你那里的空气压力降到 0
But if you do that my body will explode!
如果那样的话我的身体会爆掉的
One... two... three... four...
一．．．二．．．三．．．四．．．